<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fundamentals on Paramjot Singh</title>
    <link>https://paramjot.io/categories/fundamentals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fundamentals on Paramjot Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 07:13:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://paramjot.io/categories/fundamentals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering R Programming</title>
      <link>https://paramjot.io/post/mastering-r-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 07:13:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paramjot.io/post/mastering-r-programming/</guid>
      <description>Functions Validating Function Inputs using Conditionals Repeating a Calculation Many Times Passing Arguments to a Function used inside User-Defined Function Peeking into a Function Where do these Functions and Objects live? Loading Objects in R Environment from R Scripts How Fast (or Slow) my Code Runs? Quick Introduction to Tibbles (and Dataframes) Exploring Built-In Datasets   In an earlier post we learned a key ingredient needed for creating any data product - atomic vectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Atomic Vectors in R</title>
      <link>https://paramjot.io/post/mastering-atomic-vectors-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:14:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paramjot.io/post/mastering-atomic-vectors-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Creating Our First Atomic Vector Peeking into our Vector Objects as Arguments to Functions Other Ways of Creating a Vector Vector Operations Chaining of Functions Selecting Few Elements of a Vector (Subsetting) More Uses of Logical Subsetting Two Types of Vectors Pick Elements Randomly Some Special Values Sequences for Loops Creating an empty vector Some Useful Vector Transformations Comparing Two Vectors Third Type of Atomic Vector Sorting Character Vectors and Changing Case Pattern Matching in Character Vectors using Regular Expressions Stringr Tools Factors - an Augmented Vector Type Summary   Atomic vectors in R are the fundamental data structures on which other more complex data structures are built.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>