<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paramjot Singh</title>
    <link>https://pchhina.github.io/portfolioSite/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Paramjot Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 05:04:40 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pchhina.github.io/portfolioSite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise Quality Prediction using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://pchhina.github.io/portfolioSite/post/exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 05:04:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pchhina.github.io/portfolioSite/post/exercise/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Many devices exists today in the market (such as Jawbone Up, Nike FuelBand, and Fitbit) inexpensively record, track and analyze data on personal physical activity. Although by using these deviices, quantiy of the physical activity is often monitored, quality is rarely quantified. In this project, our goal is be to use data from accelerometers on the belt, forearm, arm, and dumbell of 6 participants in an attempt to predict whether the activity is performed correcly or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic and Health Impact of Severe Weather Events</title>
      <link>https://pchhina.github.io/portfolioSite/post/stormdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 19:32:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pchhina.github.io/portfolioSite/post/stormdata/</guid>
      <description>Synopsis This post aims to explore the NOAA Storm Database and answer some basic questions about severe weather events focusing on their economic and health impact. The U.S. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration&amp;rsquo;s (NOAA) storm database tracks characteristics of major storms and weather events in the United States, including when and where they occur, as well as estimates of any fatalities, injuries, and property damage. The events in the database start in the year 1950 and end in November 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git commands</title>
      <link>https://pchhina.github.io/portfolioSite/post/git-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 21:40:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pchhina.github.io/portfolioSite/post/git-commands/</guid>
      <description>This is just a list of git commands I am currently using. I will keep on adding stuff to it as I use more/different commands. There are tons of tutorials out there as well as quite a few cheat sheets. While those are mostly comprehensive resources, I tend to get distracted and try to learn all commands at once without using them in real projects. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t help much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Wind Energy Production (2016)</title>
      <link>https://pchhina.github.io/portfolioSite/post/wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pchhina.github.io/portfolioSite/post/wind/</guid>
      <description>Last week I learned while listening to NPR that Texas is at the top when it comes to wind power production among all US states. While it is a suprising fact given that Texas is a conservative state and the article is an interesting read in itself, this led me to pull some data from US Department of Energy and create the map I have presented here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>