<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Paramjot Singh</title>
    <link>https://paramjot.io/categories/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Paramjot Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:14:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://paramjot.io/categories/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Atomic Vectors in R</title>
      <link>https://paramjot.io/post/mastering-atomic-vectors-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 19:14:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paramjot.io/post/mastering-atomic-vectors-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Creating Our First Atomic Vector Peeking into our Vector Objects as Arguments to Functions Other Ways of Creating a Vector Vector Operations Chaining of Functions Selecting Few Elements of a Vector (Subsetting) More Uses of Logical Subsetting Two Types of Vectors Pick Elements Randomly Some Special Values Sequences for Loops Creating an empty vector Some Useful Vector Transformations Comparing Two Vectors Third Type of Atomic Vector Sorting Character Vectors and Changing Case Pattern Matching in Character Vectors using Regular Expressions Stringr Tools Factors - an Augmented Vector Type   Atomic vectors in R are the fundamental data structures on which other more complex data structures are built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Enough... Vim</title>
      <link>https://paramjot.io/post/just-enough-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 05:05:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paramjot.io/post/just-enough-vim/</guid>
      <description>Vim is an extremely powerful editor. It is a bit scary in the beginning but once you spend a little bit time playing with it, you would start to realize its power. One of the great advantages I feel about learning Vim (when compared to a dedicated IDE) is that it is language neutral. So if you switch to learning a new language in the future, you do not have to learn the ins and outs of a new IDE, Vim will be there for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atreus Building Experience</title>
      <link>https://paramjot.io/post/atreus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 05:39:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paramjot.io/post/atreus/</guid>
      <description>Here I write about my atreus keyboard builing experience. Atreus is a keyboard with very unique features like small form factor, freedom to program any key the way you want, ability to work with any OS without installing any driver and the best of all - the freedom to build it with your own hands the way you like it. So in this regard, it is the experience of personalizing your hardware!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building R Package using Command Line</title>
      <link>https://paramjot.io/post/package_building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 05:04:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paramjot.io/post/package_building/</guid>
      <description>This post describes the process of building an R package without using RStudio. This can come in handy for anyone who is using vim (and of course Nvim-R!) as a code editor for their development work. Alright, let’s get moving. We are going to create a small package offering a new ggplot theme to demonstrate the process.
Step 0: Install the required packages
install.packages(c(&amp;quot;devtools&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;roxygen2&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;testthat&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;knitr&amp;quot;)) library(devtools) has_devel() The command has_devel() basically checks that everything is installed as expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Enough... git</title>
      <link>https://paramjot.io/post/git-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://paramjot.io/post/git-commands/</guid>
      <description>This is just a list of git commands I am currently using. There are tons of tutorials out there as well as quite a few cheat sheets. While those are mostly comprehensive resources, I tend to get distracted and try to learn all commands at once without using them in real projects. That doesn’t help much.
Initialize a local git repository
git init Cloning an existing project from github
git clone &amp;lt;project url here&amp;gt; Status Check</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>